I'm on a shock research boat up the
coast of South Africa but the actual
story begins over 7,000 miles away on
the other side of the earth and it
started as a ridiculous story I was in
Asia and I heard about a dish called
shark fin soup one bowl could cost $200
the shark bin has no flavor good eating
approves you rich and that proves you're
crazy
basically it proves you're a crazy rich
agent the least diverse movie I've ever
seen but there was a rumor that the soup
has a very special magic power is it
good for sex help with no can't help to
ask mmm
when the soup is made do they use the
whole shark fin hmm just the fin
something about this soup seemed fishy
and Hong Kong imports an insane five
thousand seven hundred tons of shark
fins a year where do you even find that
many where do you get your actual shark
fins from if they're from overseas they
come from Indonesia or Africa well I do
love burning through Comedy Central's
money so to find out more hot water
first-class ticket to South Africa I
found two shark researchers and climbed
aboard their vessel I think we're gonna
need a bigger boat
yours and we headed out onto the gentle
South African waters
that brings us to now so once I clean
this seagull off myself I gotta
test these so-called marine biologists
to see if I can truly trust them okay
I'm gonna see if your shark experts
which shock is this let's go with like a
fetal tiger shot what what sucks that is
it supposed to be a white shark it might
be easier to recognize as a white shark
if it was wearing a mag ahead you know I
don't have a television but you have a
laptop and you watch netflix non-stop
and then you brag about not having a TV
I know your kind their lack of TV no it
means that these are in fact real
scientists let's get down to business
how many sharks are killed in the world
each year seventy to a hundred million
holy hell
I thought you're gonna go 1 million 2
million a hundred million how many do
you reckon we've got left I mean we
can't even begin to answer that we know
more about the surface of the Moon that
we do our own ocean floor so you think
we really went to the moon and obviously
with sharks they're incredibly crucial
to an ecosystem most of them are top
predators in this area so what you're
saying is we need them to eat to
keep everything good you need to keep a
balance and the problem is as humans
we've tipped that balance beyond
recovery it's not just fishing fishings
a huge part of it or finning which is a
part of overfishing if you ever heard of
sharpening before
it's an incredibly brutal practice whole
sharks are brought on board and their
fins are physically cut up and the rest
of the animal's body is then Chuck back
overboard and what happens to the animal
when it sucked our hood it's like
cutting your arms and legs off and
chucking you in you've not really got
much of a chance of survival the sinks
or dive hurry painful a slow de Jesus
and it's all being done for some
bowl of soup the fin is the valuable bit
so poachers just toss the rest of the
shark away
is it happening here in South Africa the
shark finning it's happening all over
the world it's a global crisis would you
like to see like like a shark poacher
just every now and again one of them get
eaten well I just happened now in South
Africa that perches were killed by lions
and yeah that gives me an erection I
love that like someone's hunting and
then the law and eats them I feel no
pity for the for the hunter at all when
that happens I know about shakthi it's
back to Hong Kong I could have just
recorded it while I was there I want to
see the neighborhood where shark fins
are solved unsurprisingly it's super
creepy and some of them even come gift
wrapped in recent years environmental
activists have targeted these markets
which might explain all these no filming
signs that I don't give a about
where are we right now so we are in the
major shark fin trade hub in the world
Diego Karan OSA is an expert on the
shark fin trader who was the first guy
to cut one off and go this would taste
good seems like a big leap to me yeah
but it was like many many centuries ago
there that happened they're obviously
not hiding this is very clearly out in
the open so this isn't a thing that that
are done in back alleys or behind closed
doors there's nothing illegal in Hong
Kong or there's not any law that would
prohibit you to have things like this
see buying a shark fin is legal in much
of the world including a lot of the u.s.
as long as the entire shark is brought
back to the shore and used but when you
just see a fin in the shop window dad
feel if it's from a hammerhead that came
illegally once is in the shops there's
no way if it came illegally or
so it's like blundered almost right are
these sharks in danger some species are
how many animals did she kill to get
that I'll tell you
zero given yes these days people
who give zero are everywhere so
selfishly I want to see some sharks up
close before it's too late and I've
always wanted to do a shark dive there's
a safe right
see why not so it's time to add a name
to history's greatest sea explorers
Cousteau Cameron and now Jeffries that's
called holy balls that's cold
all right just don't yourself
I wish I could say this really happened
but we had to fake it for TV because
actually we didn't see one shark just a
bloody seal
this happens on a lot of shark dives but
we're dangerously close to making this a
permanent reality how do we solve this
problem well it's a really complex
situation because obviously the demand
is constantly there research is key and
in certainly support for marine science
is crucial was crucial to the health of
our planet so news flash
buying a shark fin will not help you
fight better but if you still believe
otherwise after watching this then I can
guarantee no one wants to you so
let the local our wallets to support
research before it's too late
[Music]